请问 先生 这里有洗手间吗?
Excuse me, sir,\nis there a commode?
Justin!
快 亲爱的 给我拍张手举金字塔的照片
Quick, honey, take my picture.\nI got the pyramid in my hand.
Justin 你快给我回来!
Justin, you get back here\nright now!
不 站住!
No, stop!
- 不 不! 拦住他!\n- 快回去! 别爬!
- No, no! Stop him!\n- Go back! Don't climb!
等等 等等
Wait, wait.
别动 放松 小朋友
Hold on. Easy, little boy.
好了 站住 孩子! 站着别动 不!
Okay, stop, child!\nStop right there. No!
不 不 不! 他掉下去了
No, no, no! There he goes.
Justin!
我能接住! 我能接住!
I've got him! I've got him!
今晚 埃及曝出一条爆炸性的新闻
Outrage in Egypt tonight\nas it was discovered
胡夫金字塔遭人偷走
that the Great Pyramid of Giza\nhad been stolen
取而代之的竟然是一只巨大的充气仿制品
and replaced\nby a giant inflatable replica.
事件引起全球恐慌 各国人民
There is panic throughout the globe\nas countries and citizens
都在尽力保护自己国家的地标
try to protect\ntheir beloved landmarks.
执法部门仍然毫无线索
Law enforcement\nstill has no leads,
大家都在猜测 到底哪个大坏蛋
leaving everyone to wonder,\nwhich of the world's villains
才是这起卑劣罪行的主谋
is responsible\nfor this heinous crime?
他的下一步行动又是什么?
And where will he strike next?
今天我心情很坏很坏
I'm having a bad, bad day
于是现在 火力全开
It's about time\nthat I get my way
眼前的一切全都碾烂
Steamrolling whatever I see
冷冻光线! 冷冻光线! 冷冻光线!
Freeze ray!\nFreeze ray! Freeze ray!
今天我心情很坏很坏
I'm having a bad, bad day
你要因此恨我 我也不会记怀
If you take it personal,\nthat's okay
看好了 这可不好玩
Watch, this is so fun to see
因为我是大坏蛋
Despicable me
早啊 Gru!
Morning, Gru!
你好啊
How you doing?
你好 Fred
Hello, Fred.
提醒你一下 你家的狗把我家院子\n拉得到处都是狗屎
FYI, your dog has been leaving\nlittle bombs all over my yard,
这我可不喜欢
and I don't appreciate it.
抱歉 这也没办法\n狗就是喜欢到处乱跑
Sorry. You know dogs.\nThey go wherever they want to go.
死了就不会乱跑了
Unless they're dead.
我开玩笑的!
I'm joking!
可我也没说错 祝你愉快
Although, it is true.\nAnyway, have a good one.
好吧
Okay. Yeah.
眼前的一切全都碾烂
Steamrolling whatever I see
因为我是大坏蛋
Despicable me
今天我心情很坏很坏
I'm having a bad, bad day
你要因此恨我 我也不会记怀
If you take it personal,\nthat's okay
因为我是大坏蛋
Despicable me
开什么玩笑!
You've got to be pulling on my leg!
有人吗?
Hello!
要买饼干吗?
Cookies for sale.
走开 家里没人
Go away. I'm not home.
有人 我听见你说话了
Yes, you are. I heard you.
不 你没听见 这是
No, you didn't. This
这是录音
is a recording.
- 不 不是录音\n- 就是录音
- No, it isn't.\n- Yes, it is.
听好了 有事请留言 哔--
Watch this. Leave a message, beep.
再见了 录音先生
Goodbye, recorded message.
Agnes 快跟上
Agnes, come on.
Kyle!
坏狗狗! 不! 不 不\n坐下 我的小松饼
Bad dog! No! No, no.\nSit. My muffin.
Gru!
Nefario博士
Dr Nefario.
我知道你现在是什么感觉
I know how you must be feeling.
因为我也一样 正承受着巨大的挫败感
I, too, have encountered\ngreat disappointment,
但你在我眼里 永远都是最伟大的
but in my eyes,\nyou will always be one of the greats.
怎么了? 出什么事了?
What? What happened?
新闻上都在播呢!
It's all over the news!
某个家伙盗走了一座金字塔
Some fella just stole a pyramid.
他们都说跟他相比\n我们这些其他坏蛋都...
They're saying he makes\nall other villains look
太菜了
lame.
集合喽罗们开会!
Assemble the minions!
喽们 集合了!
Minions, assemble!
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
嘿!
Hey!
气色不错啊 Kevin!\n家里人都好吗?
Looking good, Kevin!\nHow is the family? Good?
很好
All right.
这才是我的小Billy! 你好吗 Larry?
That's my Billy boy!\nWhat up, Larry?
大家好!
Hello, everybody!
很好 很好!
Yeah, all right!
安静 安静!
Simmer down. Simmer down!
谢谢 好了
Thank you, okay.
我想你们也应该都听说了
Now, I realize that you guys\nprobably heard
某个坏蛋偷走了金字塔
about this other villain\nwho stole the pyramids.
这确实很牛B
Apparently, it's a big deal.
人人都说这是世纪大案什么的
People are calling it the crime\nof the century and stuff like that.
我会为这个紧张吗? 不会!
But am I upset? No, I am not!
虽然有那么一丁点
A little,
但我们今年也干得不错
but we have had\na pretty good year ourselves,
你们的名字全都记在功劳簿上了
and you guys\nare all right in my book.
不 别得意!
No, no raises!
你们都没什么好得意的
You're not going to get\nany raises.
我们都做了些什么?
What did we do?
我们偷走了时代广场上的大屏幕!
Well, we stole\nthe Times Square JumboTron!
漂亮!
Nice!
这就是我的风格
That's how I roll.
你们都喜欢用那东西看橄榄球是吧?
Yeah, you all like watching football\non that, huh?
还不止这些
But that's not all.
我们还偷走了自由女神像
We stole the Statue of Liberty,
虽然是拉斯维加斯那个迷你版的
the small one from Las Vegas.
还有艾菲尔铁塔! 也是拉斯维加斯的
And I won't even mention\nthe Eiffel Tower! Also Vegas.
好吧 我当时还不想说
Okay, I wasn't going to tell you\nabout this yet,
其实我正在策划一项大工程!
but I have been working\non something very big!
金字塔那事跟它根本没法比!
Something that will blow this\npyramid thing out of the water!
这还多亏了我的好朋友Nefario博士...
And thanks to the efforts\nof my good friend Dr Nefario...
谢谢!
Thank you!
他来了
There he is.
看他多有型
He's styling.
我们查到一间秘密实验室里
Now, we have located a shrink ray
藏着缩小射线 只要我们把它到手
in a secret lab,\nand once we take this shrink ray,
我们就能够
we will have the capability
犯下真正意义上的世纪大案
to pull off the true crime\nof the century.
我们要去偷的是...
We are going to steal...
等等 等等! 我还没说是什么呢
Wait, wait!\nI haven't told you what it is yet.
嘿
Hey.
Dave 注意听好了
Dave, listen up, please.
接下来 我们要去偷的是
Next, we are going to steal,
这时候停顿一下才给力
pause for effect,
月球!
the moon!
一旦月球落到我手里
And once the moon is mine,
想要我交出来的话\n整个世界都得满足我的任何条件!
the world will give me\nwhatever I want to get it back!
而我就会成为前无古人\n后无来者的超级大坏蛋!
And I will be the greatest villain\nof all time!
这就是我要说的
That's what I'm talking about.
喂?
Yes?
喂 Gru? 我做了下预算
Hello, Gru?\nI've been crunching some numbers,
我们可没那么多钱玩这个
and I really don't see\nhow we can afford this.
根本就不可行 我可创造不了奇迹
It can't be done.\nI'm not a miracle worker.
嘿 别紧张
Hey, chillax.
我再去银行贷笔款 他们都喜欢我!
I'll just get another loan\nfrom the bank. They love me!
Edith 别玩了!
Edith, stop it!
干嘛? 我就走路嘛
What? I'm just walking.
"Hattie小姐女童收留所"
- 嗨 Hattie小姐 我们回来了\n- 嗨 Hattie小姐 我们回来了
- Hi, Miss Hattie. We're back.\n- Hi, Miss Hattie. We're back.
你们好 姑娘们!
Hello, girls!
我们不在的时候 有人来领养我们吗?
Anybody come to adopt us\nwhile we were out?
我想想
Let me think.
没有!
No!
Edith! 你把什么放我桌上了?
Edith!\nWhat did you put on my desk?
泥巴派
A mud pie.
你这样可别想有人来领养\nEdith 知道吗?
You're never gonna get adopted, Edith.\nYou know that, don't you?
- 知道了\n- 很好
- Yeah, I know.\n- Good.
那么 指标完成得怎么样啊? 姑娘们
So, how did it go, girls?\nDid we meet our quotas?
还行
Sort of.
我们卖了43个薄荷饼干 30个巧克力卷\n还有18个椰子饼干
We sold 43 mini-mints,\n30 choco-swirlies,\nand 18 coco-nutties.
好吧
Okay.
你是说 今天卖得很不错喽
Well, you say that\nlike it's a great sale day.
你看我的表情!
Look at my face!
你还觉得今天卖得不错吗?
Do you still think\nit's a great sale day?
18个椰子饼干
Eighteen coco-nutties.
我想你们还能做得好些 是不是啊?
I think we can do a little better\nthan that, don't you?
是啊
Yeah.
你们都不想在周末关小黑屋吧?\n不想
We wouldn't want to spend the weekend\nin the Box of Shame, would we? No.
- 不想 Hattie小姐\n- 不想 Hattie小姐
- No, Miss Hattie.\n- No, Miss Hattie.
很好 走吧 把我的衣服洗了
Okay, good. Off you go.\nGo clean something of mine.
- 嗨 Penny\n- 嗨 Penny
- Hi, Penny.\n- Hi, Penny.
嗨 你们好
Hi, guys.
喂 妈妈 抱歉\n我想给你打电话的来着 可是...
Hello, Mom.\nSorry, I meant to call, but...
我是来祝贺你把金字塔搞到手的
I just wanted to congratulate you\non stealing the pyramid.
是你干的 对吗?
That was you, wasn't it?
还有哪个坏蛋能这么牛B呢?
Or was it a villain\nwho's actually successful?
就像您说的 妈妈 我是在准备一件
Just so you know, Mom,\nI am about to do something
惊天动地的大事
that's very, very big,\nvery important.
你知道后 会为我非常骄傲的
When you hear about it,\nyou're going to be very proud.
那祝你好运吧 好了 我要挂了
Good luck with that.\nOkay, I'm out of here.
"坏蛋银行"
我是Gru 来找Perkins先生
Gru to see Mr. Perkins.
好的 找个位子坐一下
Yes, please have a seat.
这对我来说也许只是一小步
That's one small step for man,
但对整个人类却是一个跨越
one giant leap for mankind.
妈妈 我以后也要登月
Ma, someday\nI'm going to go to the moon.
恐怕你这话说晚了 儿子
I'm afraid you're too late, Son.
宇航局不再送猴子去做试验了
NASA isn't sending\nthe monkeys any more.
嘿
Hey.
哥在申请做新坏蛋的贷款\n以Vector (向量)的名义
I'm applying for a new villain loan.\nGo by the name of Vector.
这是个数学名词
It's a mathematical term,
就是带箭头的物理量 既有方向又有能量
a quantity represented by an arrow,\nwith both direction and magnitude.
Vector! 就是哥
Vector! That's me,
因为哥作的案既有方向又有能量
'cause I'm committing crimes\nwith both direction and magnitude.
哦也!
Oh, yeah!
看看我新发明的武器
Check out my new weapon.
食人鱼发射枪! 哦也!
Piranha gun! Oh, yes!
能发射活的食人鱼 见过没?\n当然没见过了 这可是哥发明的
Fires live piranhas.\nEver seen one before?\nNo, you haven't.\nI invented it.
要给你做个演示吗?
Do you want a demonstration?
妈的!\n有时候要把食人鱼装回去还真不简单...
Shoot! So difficult, sometimes,\nto get the piranha back inside of my...
Gru先生 Perkins先生现在可以见你了
Mr. Gru, Mr. Perkins will see you now.
于是 我只需要
So, all I need
银行能贷款给我造火箭
is money from the bank\nto build a rocket.
- 那样的话 月球就是我们的了\n- 哇哦!
- And then, the moon is ours.\n- Wow!
这提议真给力
Well, very nice presentation.
我想看看这缩小射线
I'd like to see this shrink ray.
那是当然了! 只要一到手就给你看
Absolutely! Will do.\nSoon as I have it.
这么说还没到手?
You don't have it?
那你还有脸来银行借钱?
And yet you have the audacity\nto ask the bank for money?
看来是这样
Apparently.
你知道银行在你身上花多少钱了吗 Gru?
Do you have any idea of the capital that this bank\nhas invested in you, Gru?
你那些能真正赚钱的邪恶计划少得可怜
With far too few of your sinister plots\nactually turning a profit.
你叫我怎么忍受你? 好比你就是这个苹果
How can I put it?\nLet's say this apple is you.
如果你没办法把那些钱都赢回来...
If we don't start getting\nour money back...
明白没?
Get the picture?
听着 Gru 关键是\n现在新出道的坏蛋很多很多
Look, Gru, the point is, there are\na lot of new villains out there,
比你年轻 也比你更渴望成功
younger than you,\nhungrier than you,
比你年轻
younger than you.
就像门外那个叫Vector的年轻人
Like that young fellow out there\nnamed Vector.
金字塔就是他偷的!
He just stole a pyramid!
明白了 明白了
I've got it. I've got it.
这么说 要想贷款造火箭...
So, as far as getting money\nfor the rocket...
就去把缩小射线弄来 否则免谈
Get the shrink ray,\nthen we'll talk.
"东亚某秘密研究基地"
傻B!
Suckers!
到手了!
We got it!
怎么回事?
What?
嘿! 嘿! 怎么回事! 嘿!
Hey! Hey! What! Hey!
不 不 不!
No, no, no!
是你!
You!
以后冻住别人脑袋之前先想清楚
Now, maybe you'll think twice\nbefore you freeze someone's head!
后会有期了 Gru!
So long, Gru!
快! 别让他跑了
Quick! We can't let him get away!
正前方! 正前方!
Up ahead! Up ahead!
开火! 快开火!
Fire! Fire, now!
你没打中!
You missed me!
让爷来教训你!
Come to papa!
尝尝这个
Take that.
真可爱
How adorable.
这下你跑不掉了!
Got you in our sights!
就像是探囊取...
Like taking candy from a...
什么?
What?
嘿 Gru!
Hey, Gru!
看看飞船变小会怎么样!
Try this on for size!
这太诡异了 怎么...
That's weird. What is going...
我会得幽闭恐惧症的!
This is claustrophobic!
不 不 不!
No, no, no!
太小了! 这太小了!
Too small!\nThis is too small for me!
我恨那小子!
I hate that guy!
...请照看我们 保佑我们睡个好觉
...and please watch over us, and bless\nthat we'll have a good night's sleep.
保佑我们在睡觉的时候\n不会有虫子爬进耳朵
And bless that while we're sleeping,\nno bugs will crawl into our ears
在我们脑子里产卵
and lay eggs in our brains.
很好 谢谢你生动的描述 Edith
Great.\nThanks for that image, Edith.
还有请保佑我们很快就有人收养
And please bless\nthat someone will adopt us soon,
爸爸妈妈都对我们很好
and that the mommy and daddy\nwill be nice
我也能有只独角兽做宠物
and have a pet unicorn.
阿门
Amen.
- 阿门\n- 阿门
- Amen.\n- Amen.
独角兽 我喜欢\n独角兽 我喜欢
Unicorns, I love them\nUnicorns, I love them
独角 独角兽 我喜欢
Uni, uni, unicorns\nI love them
独角 独角兽 养只做宠物
Uni, unicorns,\nI could pet one
如果真的有独角兽
If they were really real
如果你们是真的
And they are
那我就能买一只来做宠物
So, I bought one\nso I could pet it
它爱我 我也爱它
Now it loves me\nNow I love it
"Vector的城堡"
"安全警报"
这是...开什么玩笑...
Don't you... What the...
祝你们好运 小萝莉!
Good luck, little girls!
哇哦 真酷!
Whoa! Cool.
嗨 我们是Hattie女童收留所的孤儿
Hi! We're orphans\nfrom Miss Hattie's Home for Girls.
- 我不管 快滚!\n- 别这样!
- I don't care. Beat it!\n- Come on!
我们得多卖饼干 才可能有好前途
We're selling cookies so,\nyou know, we can have a better future.
- 等等! 你们有椰子饼干吗?\n- 有啊
- Wait, wait!\nDo you have coco-nutties? - Yeah.
有办法了
Light bulb.
Nefario博士!
Dr Nefario!
给我造些饼干外形的微型小机器人!
I'm going to need a dozen tiny robots\ndisguised as cookies!
- 什么?\n- 饼干机器人!
- What?\n- Cookie robots!
- 你谁啊?\n- 哦 算了吧
- Who is this?\n- Oh, forget it.
看来你的背景符合我们的要求
Well, it appears you have cleared\nour background check,
Gru医生
Dr Gru.
我看见你整理的那张
And I see you have made a list
对你颇有好评的病人名单了
of some of your personal achievements.
谢谢 我就爱看这个
Thank you for that.\nI love reading.
你得过荣誉勋章
And I see you have been given\nthe Medal of Honor
还曾受爵位
and a knighthood.
- 我 我 我\n- 我 我 我
- Me, me, me.\n- Me, me, me.
Kevin?
你有过自己的厨艺节目
You had your own cooking show
能屏住呼吸30秒?
and you can hold your breath\nfor 30 seconds?
这很一般嘛
It's not that impressive.
白痴!
Idiot!
- 打! 打! 打! 打!\n- 打! 打! 打! 打!
- Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!\n- Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
这都是些什么啊?
What in the name of... What?
好 那就这样吧
Well, here's the dealio.
自从我妻子Debbie过世后
Things have been\nso lonely since my wife,
我的人生就孤单起来
Debbie, passed on.
就好比 我的心是颗牙齿
It's like my heart is a tooth,
而牙齿上蛀了个洞\n只有孩子的爱才能填补好这个洞
and it's got a cavity\nthat can only be filled with children.
请原谅
I'm sorry.
你很漂亮 你会说西班牙语吗?
You are a beautiful woman.\nDo you speak Spanish?
你看我像是会说西班牙语吗?
Do I look like I speak Spanish?
你的脸生得五六肿额
You have a face como un burro.
哦 谢谢!
Well, thank you!
言归正传 能继续谈收养问题了吗?
Anyway, can we proceed\nwith this adoption?
我都迫不及待了!
So, so excited!
去叫Margo, Edith和Agnes到前厅来
Please tell Margo, Edith and Agnes\nto come to the lobby.
我猜妈妈一定很漂亮!
I bet the mom is beautiful!
我猜爸爸的眼神很动人
I bet the daddy's eyes sparkle.
我猜他们家里有的是大熊软糖
I bet their house\nis made of Gummi Bears.
就是说他们家会很漂亮
I'm just saying it'd be nice.
我的毛毛虫变不成蝴蝶了
My caterpillar\nnever turned into a butterfly.
那是奇多
That's a Cheeto.
Debbie是个很幸运的女人
Well, Debbie was a very lucky woman.
Debbie是谁?
Who's Debbie?
你妻子啊
Your wife.
嗨 丫头们!
Hi, girls!
姑娘们 来见见Gru先生
Girls, I want you to meet Mr. Gru.
他是来收养你们的
He's going to adopt you.
他是牙医哦!
And he's a dentist!
真棒!
Yeah!
嗨 我是Margo 这是Edith
Hi. I'm Margo. This is Edith.
那是Agnes
And that's Agnes.
我抓住你腿了 我抓住你腿了!
I got your leg, I got your leg!
好啦 差不多行了 小丫头
Okay, that is enough, little girl.
- 放开我的腿 快 你知道怎么做的\n- 再高点!
- Let go of my leg. Come on.\nYou can do it. - Higher!
- 再高点!\n- 你只要撒开手就行 哇!
- Higher!\n- Just release your grip. Wow!
你平时都是怎么弄开的? 有什么口令吗?
How do you remove them?\nIs there a command?
还是用了什么不粘材料?
Some nonstick spray?
撬棍?
Crowbar?
好了 丫头们 我们走吧
Okay, girls, let's go.
哦也!
Oh, yeah!
相当震惊
Pretty impressive!
你看什么看?
What are you looking at?
找灭!
Boo-ya!
你缩水啦 小小漱口剂
You got shrunk, tiny mouthwash!
看招!
Take that!
你完蛋了!
You done been shrunk!
喂?
Yello?
我顺利搞到缩小射线了
I got the shrink ray, all right.
没 我才没拿着它乱玩呢
No, I'm not playing with it.
Gru?
别逗了! 没有
Don't make me laugh! No.
再说 他不可能偷到月亮的
P.S., he is not getting the moon,
再再说 等哥摆平他以后
and P.P.S., by the time\nI'm done with him,
他就只有求饶的份了
he's gonna be begging for mercy.
好的 拜
Okay, bye.
迷你小宝贝 专用的迷你小马桶
Look at you, a little tiny toilet\nfor a little tiny baby...
我咒你全家 破迷你马桶
Curse you, tiny toilet!
好了 我们到了
Okay, here we are.
甜蜜温馨的家
Home sweet home.
这 就是你家?
So, this is, like, your house?
稍等片刻...
Wait a sec...
你就是那个假装自动答录机的人!
You're the guy who pretended\nhe was a recorded message!
不是 那是别人干的
No, that was someone else.
你可以牵着我吗?
Can I hold your hand?
不行
No.
从我们被这光头佬收养的那一刻起\n我就觉得我们会落得像Annie那么惨
When we got adopted by a bald guy,\nI thought this'd be more like Annie.
别咬 嘿!
No, hey!
Kyle 这些不是供你享用的\n这些是我们的客人
Kyle, these are not treats.\nThese are guests.
孩子们 这是Kyle 我的...
Girls, this is Kyle, my
狗
dog.
毛茸茸的狗狗
Fluffy doggy!
这是什么品种的狗?
What kind of dog is that?
它是... 我不知道
He is a... I don't know.
你真的觉得这里适宜小朋友居住吗?
Do you really think that this is\nan appropriate place for little kids?
显然不合适
'Cause it's not.
别 不要! 快出来!
No! No! Stay away from there!
它经不起折腾的
It's fragile.
好吧 我看计划要改成两个人了
Well, I suppose\nthe plan will work with two.
嘿! 这里面好暗啊
Hey! It's dark in here.
它把我的果汁戳了个洞
It poked a hole in my juice box.
如你们所见
As you can see,
我已经准备好了小孩子\n可能用得上的所有东西
I have provided everything\na child might need.
行了
All right.
就像我说的... 嘿!
Okay. As I was saying... Hey!
有人把它打破了
Somebody broke that.
好了 够了 很明显 我们得立些规矩
Okay, okay.\nClearly, we need to set some rules.
规矩一
Rule number one.
不准碰任何东西
You will not touch anything.
那地板呢?
What about the floor?
好的 你们可以踩在地板上!
Yes, you may touch the floor.
那空气呢?
What about the air?
好的 你们可以接触空气!
Yes, you may touch the air!
那这个呢?
What about this?
- 你从哪儿拿的?\n- 我找到的
- Where did you get that?\n- Found it.
好了 规矩二 我工作的时候不准打扰我
Okay. Rule number two. You will not\nbother me while I'm working.
规矩三
Rule number three.
不准大哭 抽泣 大笑 或者咯咯笑
You will not cry or whine\nor laugh or giggle
也不准打喷嚏 打嗝 或者放屁!
or sneeze or burp or fart!
也就是 千万千万 千万别弄出噪音 懂了?
So, no, no, no annoying sounds.\nAll right?
这算是噪音吗?
Does this count as annoying?
绝对噪音!
Very!
我六小时后再来看你们
I will see you in six hours.
好吧 别担心 一切都会好起来的
Okay, don't worry.\nEverything's going to be fine.
我们在这会很幸福的 对吧? Agnes
We're gonna be really happy here.\nRight? Agnes?
问一下 这些是神马?
Question. What are these?
一打摇滚机器人! 动起来!
A dozen boogie robots! Boogie!
看好了 看我的!
Look at this. Watch me!
饼干机器人 我说的是饼干机器人
Cookie robots.\nI said cookie robots.
为什么... 你怎么\n你怎么就那么...守旧呢?
Why are you so old?
好吧 我会搞定的
Okay. I'm on it.
有人吗?
Hello?
电视!
TV!
那是什么?
What is that?
- 你们看呀\n- 太酷了!
- Look at that!\n- That is cool!
过来!
Come on!
我觉得他不是牙医
I don't think he's a dentist.
我们研究这个有些时日了
We've been working on this\nfor a while.
它叫做反重力糖浆
It's a anti-gravity serum.
我本打算关好窗的 他会没事的 我保证
I meant to close that.\nHe'll be all right, I'm sure.
- 药效会消失吗?\n- 目前来说
- Do the effects wear off?\n- So far,
不会 不会 现在看不会
no. No, they don't.
还有这个 毫无疑问\n是你预定的新式武器
And here, of course,\nis the new weapon you ordered.
不 不 不
No, no.
我说的是 "飞镖枪" 不是... 好了
I said "dart gun", not... Okay.
噢 这样啊 我还在奇怪
Oh, yes. 'Cause I was wondering
什么情况会用得上这玩意儿
under what circumstances\nwould we use this?
不过
But, anyway.
我真正要给你展示的是这个
What I really wanted to show you\nwas this.
这才是饼干机器人嘛!
Now those are cookie robots!
啦 啦 啦 啦 我爱独角兽
La, la, la, la\nI love unicorns
你们怎么会在这儿?\n我不是说了 在厨房带着吗?
What are you doing here?\nI told you to stay in the kitchen!
我们太无聊了 这里是干嘛用的?
We got bored.\nWhat is this place?
这个我能喝吗?
Can I drink this?
你想玩自爆吗?
Do you want to explode?
Gru!
回厨房去!
Get back in the kitchen!
- 你会和我们玩吗?\n- 不行
- Will you play with us?\n- No.
- 为什么?\n- 因为我很忙
- Why?\n- Because I'm busy.
忙什么?
Doing what?
好吧 好吧 你赢了
Okay, okay, you got me.
牙医只是我的副业
The dentist thing\nis more of a hobby.
我真正的身份是间谍
In real life, I am a spy.
这是最高机密 你们不可以跟任何人说
And it is top secret,\nand you may not tell anybody,
- 因为如果你们说了...\n- 这是用来做什么的?
- because if you do...\n- What does this do?
嘿!
Hey!
我的独角兽!
My unicorn!
你得把它修好
You have to fix it.
修? 它已经化成灰了\n也就是说 它不可能修好了
Fix it? Look,\nit has been disintegrated.\nBy definition, it cannot be fixed.
别吓我 她这是要干嘛?
That's freaking me out.\nWhat is she doing?
她会一直摒着气 直到给她个新独角兽
She's gonna hold her breath\nuntil she gets a new one.
那只是个玩具而已 别闹了
It is just a toy. Now stop it!
好啦 好啦 我会把它修好
Okay, okay! I'll fix it!
Tim! Mark! Phil!
这非常重要
This is very important.
你们必须给这个丫头弄个新独角兽玩偶
You have to get the little girl\na new unicorn toy.
嘿 嘿 嘿! 是玩偶
Hey, hey, hey! A toy!
去吧 要快!
Go, and hurry!
那些是什么?
What are those?
他们是 我的表亲
They are my cousins.
Jerry! Stuart!
看好她们 让她们离我远点
Watch them, and keep them\naway from me, please.
Wow!
这是你表弟的主意
It was your cousin's idea.
什么?
What?
好了 该去睡觉了
Okay, bedtime.
没说你们俩!
Not you two!
好啦 睡觉觉 盖好被被 做个好梦
Okey-dokey. Beddie-bye.\nAll tucked in. Sweet dreams.
你要知道
Just so you know,
你永远都不会成为我爸爸
you're never gonna be my dad.
我不会介意的
I think I can live with that.
这些床是用炸弹做的吗?
Are these beds\nmade out of bombs?
没错 不过它们已经老得不可能爆炸了
Yes, but they are very old\nand highly unlikely to blow up.
不过还是不要翻来翻去的
But try not to toss and turn.
酷
Cool.
- 你会给我们讲睡前故事吗?\n- 不会
- Will you read us\na bedtime story? - No.
不听故事我们会睡不着的
But we can't go to sleep\nwithout a bedtime story.
那么 你的夜晚注定格外漫长了
Well, then it's going to be\na long night for you, isn't it?
那么 晚安 好好睡 当心别被虫子咬了
So, good night, sleep tight,\nand don't let the bed bugs bite.
这里的虫子超多的哦
Because there are literally\nthousands of them.
另外 你们的衣橱里可能会有什么东西哟
And there's probably\nsomething in your closet.
他开玩笑的 Agnes
He's just kidding, Agnes.
好可爱哦
It's beautiful.
姑娘们 出发了
Girls, let's go.
送饼干去喽
Time to deliver the cookies!
没问题 但我们要先去上舞蹈课
Okay. But first,\nwe're going to dance class.
事实上 今天我们不会去上舞蹈课
Actually, we're going to have to\nskip the dance class today.
事实上 我们今天必须去上舞蹈课
Actually, we can't\nskip the dance class today.
我们马上就要有个盛大的公演了
We have a big recital coming up.
- 我们在排练《天鹅湖》的片段\n- 没错 《天鹅湖》
- We're doing an excerpt\nfrom Swan Lake. - Yeah, Swan Lake!
太好了 非常棒
That's fantastic.\nWonderful.
但我们要去送饼干了! 来吧!
But we're going to deliver cookies!\nCome on!
不要
No.
不要?
No?
不上完舞蹈课 我们是不会去送饼干的
We're not going to deliver cookies\nuntil we do dance class.
是吗?
Really?
我不会开车送你们去的
Well, I am not driving you\nto dance class.
要是你们想去 就自己走去吧
So if you want to go, you are going to\nhave to walk yourselves.
你们干吗?
What are you doing?
走去上舞蹈课
Walking to dance class.
你们! 好吧 好啦
Ya? Okay, fine.
慢走啊 我是绝对不会送你们去的
You just keep walking,\nbecause I'm really not driving you!
好的
Okay.
Gru很生气 后果很严重
You're going to suffer\nthe wrath of Gru!
我说真的 我数三下
Seriously,\nI'm going to count to three!
你们最好给我到车里去
And you had better be in this car!
我要数咯! 一! 二!
Here we go! One! Two!
... 三 四 五
...three, four and five.
抬 伸
And lift, and stretch.
一  二
And one, and two...
- 给你\n- 这是什么?
- Here you go.\n- What is it?
我们公演的门票 你会来的 对吧?
Your ticket to the dance recital.\nYou are coming, right?
当然 当然
Of course, of course.
我简直如坐针毡的
I have pins and needles\nthat I'm sitting on.
勾手指?
Pinkie promise?
好的 耍赖的是小狗
Oh, yes. My pinkie promises.
好啦 我们的第一位顾客叫做Vector
All right. Our first customer\nis a man named Vector.
但他是V字头
But he's a V.
我们应该先从A字头的开始
You know, we're supposed\nto start with the A's.
然后是B字头 然后我们...
Then we go to the B's. Then we...
没错 是的 我上过幼儿园\n我知道26个字母的顺序
Yes, yes! I went to kindergarten.\nI know how the alphabet works!
我 我只是觉得
I was just thinking
先给Vector先生送去会比较好
that it might be nice\nto deliver Mr. Vector's first.
就这样
That is all.
快结束了 就快成功了
Almost over. It's almost over.
姑娘们 欢迎回到Vector的城堡
Girls, welcome back\nto the fortress of Vector-tude!
你们把我要的饼干带来了吗?
Do you have my cookies for me?
四盒迷你薄荷糖 两条太妃糖
Four boxes of mini-mints,\ntwo toffee totes,
两块焦糖太妃 十五盒可可果仁饼干
two caramel clumpies\nand fifteen boxes of coco-nutties.
没错 我很想知道 还有谁会订那么多饼干
Exactly. I'd like to see somebody else\norder that many cookies.
不太可能
Not likely.
说出一个比我订的还要多的人
Name one person\nwho ordered more cookies than me.
一共52美元
That'll be $52.
好的
Right.
七 八 九...
Seven, eight, nine...
脑抽了! 数到哪儿了
Tic Tacs! Where was I?
七 八 九
Seven, eight, nine...
你为什么穿着睡衣?
Why are you wearing pajamas?
这不是睡衣!\n这是我的热身套装
These aren't pajamas!\nThis is a warm-up suit.
- 你为什么要热身?\n- 有事
- What are you warming up for?\n- Stuff.
什么事?
What sort of stuff?
非常带劲的事 你不会懂的
Super-cool stuff\nyou wouldn't understand.
比如睡觉?
Like sleeping?
这不是睡衣!
They are not pajamas!
给你 52块大洋
Here you go, 52 big ones.
拜!
Bye!
加油!
Come on!
这是...
What the...
安静点 大鱼
Quiet down, fish!
安静 孩子
Down, boy!
我们成功啦! 快点 姑娘们 我们走了
We did it!\nCome on, girls, let's go!
其他那些定了饼干的人怎么办?
But what about the other people\nwho ordered cookies?
生活总是不尽如人意的
Life is full of disappointments
对有的人来说
for some people.
别这么嚎了!
Don't do that!
超级淘气乐园! 我们能去吗? 拜托
Super Silly Fun Land!\nCan we go? Please?
不行
No.
但我们从来没去过\n那可是世界上最好玩的地方啊
But we've never been.\nAnd it's the funnest place on earth!
不关心
Don't care.
- 拜托\n- 拜托嘛
- Please?\n- Please?
我们以后再也不会提任何要求了
We'll never ask for anything else,\never again!
- 求求你嘛\n- 拜托啦
- Pretty please?\n- Please?
- 拜托啦!\n- 答应吧!
- Come on!\n- Come on!
有办法了
Light bulb.
快点!
Come on!
再见 玩开心点
Goodbye, have fun.
不好意思 哥们儿\n她们必须有大人陪着才能玩
Sorry, dude.\nThey can't ride without an adult.
什么?
What?
我的天啊!
Oh, my gosh!
快看那个毛茸茸的独角兽
Look at that fluffy unicorn!
它太可爱了 我受不了了
He's so fluffy, I'm gonna die!
你得让我们把它赢回来
You've gotta let us play for it!
不 不 不 不不不不
No, no, no.
来嘛!
Come on!
这个毛毛独角兽多少钱?
How much for the fluffy unicorn?
这个是非卖品
Well, it is not for sale.
你必须把那边那个宇宙飞船打倒\n才能得到这个独角兽
But all you gotta do\nto win it\nis knock down\nthat little spaceship there.
很容易的!
It's easy!
Yay!
再一次!
Again!
- 等一下\n- 拜托 再一次!
- Wait!\n- Come on. One more time!
最后一次
Just one more.
我不小心闭眼了刚刚
I accidentally closed my eyes.
- 我打到它了! 我打到它了!\n- 好厉害
- I hit it! I hit it!\n- That was cool.
哇 哇 哇 这算什么?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What was that?
她打到了 我明明看到了
She hit that.\nI saw that with my own eyes.
嘿 老兄 我给你解释解释
Hey, buddy,\nlet me explain something to you.
看到那个小宇宙飞船了吗?\n你看 它还没有被打倒吧?
You see that little tin spaceship?\nYou see how it's not knocked over?
你知道这是什么意思吗 教授?
Do you know what that means,\nprofessor?
意思就是 你得不到那个独角兽!
It means you don't get\nthe unicorn!
某人的脸很难看哦
Somebody's got a frowny face.
好怕怕! 下次好运
Boo! Better luck next time!
好了 我来
Okay, my turn.
倒了吧!
Knocked over!
- 好软啊\n- 是呀
- It's so fluffy!\n- Yeah!
你太强了!
That was awesome!
你把那些都炸了!
You blew up the whole thing!
我们走吧 去玩其他的游戏!
Let's go.\nLet's try another game!
Gru 我能跟你说几句吗?
Gru, do you mind\nif I have a quick word?
好啦 姑娘们 去玩吧
Okay, girls, go play.
我拿到缩小射线了!
I got the shrink ray!
棉花糖!
Cotton candy!
距离月亮到达对我们\n最有利的位置只有12天了
We have 12 days\nuntil the moon is in optimum position.
我们不能再东拉西扯了!
We can't afford any distractions!
帮我接通Perkins
Get me Perkins.
抱歉打扰你 Perkins先生
Sorry to bother you, Mr. Perkins,
但我认为 你会很想看看这个
but I figured\nthat you would want to see this!
什么?
What?
做得好 Gru 出乎意料
Well done, Gru.\nRather impressive.
现在 剩下的事就简单多了
Now, the rest of the plan\nis simple.
我飞去月亮上 把月亮缩小
I fly to the moon.\nI shrink the moon.
我把月亮拿走 然后我坐在马桶上
I grab the moon.\nI sit on the toilet.
什么?
What?
不好意思 不好意思!
Sorry. Sorry!
您能稍等下吗?
Could you excuse me\nfor just one second?
我跟你们说 不要碰我的东西
I told you not to touch my things.
我说了又说 我跟你们说了一百遍了
I told you, I told you.\nI've told you a thousand times.
嘿 我们能叫份披萨吗?
Hey, can we order pizza?
披萨? 你们不是刚吃的中饭吗?
Pizza? You just had lunch.
不是现在吃 当晚饭
Not now, for dinner.
晚饭?
Dinner?
那... 好吧 好吧 好吧 随你们\n乖乖到里面去
Just... Fine, fine, fine, whatever.\nJust get back in there!
我们能点厚底披萨吗?
Can we get stuffed crust?
- 厚底披萨!\n- 厚底披萨!
- Stuffed crust!\n- Stuffed crust!
我要把你们全包进面皮里
I'll stuff you all in the crust!
你好好笑!
You're funny!
别再踏出那房间一步了!
Just don't come out of that room\nagain!
好了
All right.
不好意思 刚刚说到哪儿了
Sorry about that.\nWhere were we?
你坐在马桶上
You were sitting on the toilet.
不 不 不 不是 抱歉\n那只是我小幽默一下
No, no, no! No, I'm sorry.\nIt was a little attempt at humor.
我知道你超爱笑的...
I know how much you like to laugh
你 内心深处\n现在 我要说的是...
inside. Now, I was saying...
看来你精力不太集中 Gru
You don't seem terribly focused, Gru.
相信我 我绝对全神贯注
Believe me,\nI am completely focused.
- 你好!\n- 什么?
- Hello!\n- What?
这有个巨人!
That guy is huge!
- 我们上电视了吗?\n- 那是什么? 哪来的孩子?
- Are we on TV?\n- What are those? Children?
你们又要干嘛? 跟你们说了别过来!
What are you doing?\nI told you to stay out of here!
不要!
No, no, no!
冰冻射线!
Freeze ray!
Gru先生?
Mr. Gru?
好的
Okay.
我刚才说...
As I was saying...
别说了 够了
No need to continue.\nI've seen quite enough.
- 但是我的计划...\n- 很好
- But my plan...\n- Is a great plan.
计划很好 美中不足的
I love everything about your plan,\nexcept for one thing.
是你
You.
看 妈妈 我画了张自己登月的画!
Look, Mom, I drew a picture of me\nlanding on the moon!
看 妈妈 我用通心粉做了个微型火箭!
Look, Mom, I made a prototype\nof the rocket out of macaroni!
妈妈\n我照着通心粉火箭模型造了个真家伙!
Look, Mom, I made a real rocket\nbased on the macaroni prototype!
我不明白
I don't understand.
面对现实吧 Gru
Let's face reality, Gru.
这个计划你已经跟进这么久了\n却没取得什么进展
You've been at this for far too long\nwith far too little success.
所以银行决定 转而投资...
We're gonna put our faith,\nour money, into a...
更年轻的坏蛋
Well, a younger villain.
可是我...
But I...
就这样吧 再见 Gru
It's over. Goodbye, Gru.
我知道现在有些谣言
Now, I know there have been\nsome rumors going around
说银行已经撤资了
that the bank\nis no longer funding us.
我觉得需要出来说明一下
Well, I am here\nto put those rumors to rest.
谣言是真的
They are true.
关于投资
In terms of money,
我们没钱了
we have no money.
那还怎么登月呢?
So how will we get to the moon?
答案很明显
The answer is clear.
我们去不成了
We won't.
我们完了
We are doomed.
也许你们可以现在可以考虑另谋高就了
Now would probably be a good time\nto look for other employment options.
不过我知道
I know.
我把自己的履历烧掉了
I have fired up my resume
我同样建议你们也这样做
as I suggest\nthat all of you do, as well.
你们在这干吗?
What is it?
没看见我正在鼓舞士气吗?
Can't you see that I am\nin the middle of a pep talk?
对啊!
Yes!
没错 我们自己造火箭
Yes, we will build our own rocket
竭尽所能 我们可以的!
using this and whatever else\nwe can find!
什么都行! 刨垃圾堆! 把车拆了!
Grab everything! Hit the junkyards!\nTake apart the cars!
谁他妈需要什么银行?
Who needs the bank?
开始行动 动起来!
Let's go. Let's go!
临界危险
已安全
妈! 你怎么来了?
Mom! What are you doing here?
当时我正给他洗澡
And here he is in the bathtub.
看他的小屁屁
Look at his little buns.
妈
Mom.
一点都不好玩
Not cool.
这张 他当时要去做礼拜
And here, he's all dressed up\nin his Sunday best.
真像个女孩!
He looks like a girl!
没错 不过丑了点!
Yes, he does. An ugly girl!
你太好玩了!
You're funny!
5月26号 天鹅湖公演 盗月
太棒了! 我的饼干像具尸体!
Yes! Mine's shaped like a dead guy!
Perkins先生 少爷来了
Mr. Perkins, your son is here.
让他进来
Send him in.
嗨 老爹
Hey, Dad.
你找我?
You wanted to see me?
- 是的 Victor\n- 我现在不叫Victor了
- Yes, I did, Victor.\n- I am not Victor any more.
Victor是上学时叫的 现在叫Vector!
Victor was my nerd name.\nNow I am Vector!
坐好!
Sit down!
你知道缩小射线在哪儿吗?
Do you know where the shrink ray is?
当然! 在我那呢
Duh! Back at my place.
你确定? 在你那儿? 那太好了
Oh, is that right?\nBack at your place? That's cool.
那Gru这个估计是仿制的吧!
I guess Gru must just have one\nthat looks exactly like it!
什么? 是那些卖我饼干的小女孩!
What the...\nThose girls sold me cookies!
你知道这次盗月计划可能有多赚钱吗?
Do you have any idea\nhow lucrative this moon heist could be?
我把这难得的大好良机给了你
I give you the opportunity\nof a lifetime,
你却让它打了水漂!
and you just blow it!
- 不 我没有\n- 是吗?
- No, I didn't.\n- Oh, really?
让Gru等着吧 看我的最新武器
You just wait\nuntil Gru sees my latest weapon.
乌贼喷枪! 宝贝 来吧!
Squid-launcher! Oh, yeah!
有只乌贼掉我头上了!
There's a squid on my face!
别着急
Don't worry.
月亮逃不出我们的手掌心
The moon is as good as ours.
过来 睡觉了
Come on now, it's bedtime.
你刷牙了吗? 我来闻闻
Did you brush your teeth?\nLet me smell. Let me smell.
你没刷!
You did not!
把睡衣穿上 不要乱动\n好了 说真的 别闹了
Put on your PGs. Hold still.\nOkay, seriously! Seriously!
该说晚安了 不是开玩笑 真的!
This is beddie-bye time, right now.\nI'm not kidding around. I mean it!
- 我们一点都不累!\n- 我累了
- But we're not tired!\n- Well, I am tired.
睡觉前能给我们讲个故事吗?
Will you read us a bedtime story?
不能
No.
求求你了!
Pretty please!
再怎么求也不行
The physical appearance of the "please"\nmakes no difference.
不行 赶快睡觉
It is still no, so go to sleep.
睡不着 我们好兴奋!
But we can't. We're all hyper!
如果不念 我们就一直闹啊闹地吵你
And without a bedtime story,\nwe'll just keep getting up\nand bugging you.
整个晚上哦
All night long.
你们赢了
Fine.
好吧 好吧 小猫困了
All right, all right.\nSleepy Kittens.
小猫困了?
Sleepy Kittens?
- 这是什么?\n- 手指玩偶
- What are these?\n- Puppets.
讲故事时要用到的
You use them when you tell the story.
好的 那就开始吧
Okay, let's get this over with.
"3只小猫爱玩耍 太阳下玩了一整天
"Three little kittens loved to play,\nthey had fun in the sun all day.
"妈妈过来说 宝贝们该睡觉"'
Then their mother came out and said,\n'Time for kittens to go to bed.'"
哇哦! 什么鬼东西 你们真的喜欢这个?
Wow! This is garbage.\nYou actually like this?
继续念!
Keep reading!
- 快点!\n- 好吧 那继续
- Come on!\n- All right, all right, all right.
"3只小猫大声吵
"Three little kittens started to bawl,
"妈咪 不累咋睡觉"
'Mommy, we're not tired at all.'
"妈咪笑了 喵喵说"
Their mother smiled\nand said with a purr,
"好吧 至少把毛刷刷好"
'Fine, but at least\nyou should brush your fur.'"
快刷毛毛
Now you brush the fur.
这也能出版?
This is literature?
2岁小孩都会写了 好吧
A 2-year-old could have written this.\nAll right.
"3只小猫 毛都刷刷好"
"Three little kittens\nwith fur all brushed
"大叫说 睡不着 好兴奋! '
said, 'We can't sleep,\nwe feel too rushed!'
"妈咪笑了 用缎子般的声音说"
Their mother replied,\nwith a voice like silk,
"好吧 至少把牛奶都喝掉"'
'Fine, but at least\nyou should drink your milk.'"
喂它们牛奶
Now make them drink the milk.
这本书不好 真是没完没了
I don't like this book.\nThis is going on forever.
"小猫们喝完牛奶 揉眼睛开始打哈欠"
"Three little kittens,\nwith milk all gone,\nrubbed their eyes\nand started to yawn.
"睡不着 一点都不困"
'We can't sleep,\nwe can't even try.'
接着猫妈妈唱起了摇篮曲
Then their mother sang a lullaby.
"'宝贝们晚安 闭上眼睡觉觉\n一觉睡到大天亮"
'Good night kittens, close your eyes.\nSleep in peace until you rise.
"虽然我们分开睡"
Though while you sleep,\nwe are apart,
"但妈咪永远爱你们哦"
your mommy loves you\nwith all her heart.'"
完了 好了 都晚安吧
The end. Okay, good night.
- 等下!\n- 又怎么了?
- Wait!\n- What?
睡觉前能亲下我们吗?
What about good night kisses?
不行 亲亲抱抱都不行
No, no. There will be no kissing\nor hugging or kissing.
他不会跟吻我们道晚安的 Agnes
He is not gonna kiss us\ngood night, Agnes.
我喜欢他 他真好
I like him. He's nice.
有点吓人
But scary.
像圣诞老人!
Like Santa!
还有48小时就起飞了 一切正常
Only 48 hours till the launch,\nand all systems are go.
这个啊
About that,
其实我在考虑 要不要换个时间
I was thinking that maybe\nwe could move the date of the heist.
因为那天是三个丫头的公演 是不是?
Please tell me this is not as a result\nof the girls' dance recital, is it?
当然不是!
No, no, no!
公演? 怎么会... 那么傻!
The recital? Don't... That's stupid!
我就是觉得星期天做这事很怪
I just think it's kind of weird\nto do it on a Saturday.
星期二怎么样 好不好?
I was thinking, maybe a heist\nis a Tuesday thing, right?
Gru 我们共事了那么多年
Gru, you and I have been\nworking on this for years.
这是我们的梦想啊
It's everything we've dreamed of.
你创造历史的机会来了
Your chance to make history,
盗月神偷啊!
become the man who stole the moon!
很明显孩子们让你分心了!
But these girls\nare becoming a major distraction!
他们该走了
They need to go.
如果你下不了手 我帮你
If you don't do something about it,\nthen I will.
我明白了
I understand.
很好
Good.
看他屁屁
Butt.
屁屁
好了 现在我们来碰杯
All right.\nNow, when we put our cups together,
然后说 "叮"
we will make the "clink" sound\nwith our mouths.
准备好了吗? Edith?
Ready? Edith?
- 叮\n- 叮
- Clink.\n- Clink.
来碰下 现在可以喝了
There we go. And now we drink.
接着Agnes?
And Agnes?
- 叮\n- 叮
- Clink.\n- Clink.
太棒了!
Very good!
失陪下 孩子们
Excuse me, girls.
别走嘛!
Come on!
别着急 马上回来 你们先继续
Don't worry, I'll be back.\nKeep clinking.
- 叮 叮\n- 叮 叮
- Clink, clink.\n- Clink, clink.
Hattie小姐 找我有事?
Miss Hattie,\nwhat are you doing here?
我来接孩子们\n我接到电话说 你想把她们送回来
I'm here for the girls.\nI received a call that\nyou wanted to return them.
还有 我买了本西班牙词典
And also,\nI did purchase a Spanish dictionary.
我不喜欢你说的话
I didn't like what you said.
可是...
But...
我进去帮孩子们收拾下
I will get the girls ready.
我们不想跟她走 Gru先生!
Don't let her take us, Mr. Gru!
跟她说 你舍不得我们
Tell her you wanna keep us.
好了 孩子们 我们该走了
All right, girls. Come on, let's go.
再见 Gru先生 这段时间谢谢你
Goodbye, Mr. Gru.\nThanks for everything.
我这是为了你好
I did it for your own good.
来 准备偷月亮了
Come on, let's go get that moon.
好的
Right.
这是什么?
What is this for?
公演?
The recital?
作为本世纪最伟大的犯罪头目
I am the greatest criminal mind\nof the century.
我才不去看什么公演呢!
I don't go\nto little girls' dance recitals!
开舱 准备发射\n开启发射序列
Opening launch bay doors.\nCommencing launch sequence.
准备就绪\n开始倒计10秒
And we are good to go\nin T minus 10 seconds.
10 9 8 7
6...
哦也!
Oh, yeah!
干得好 博士 一切正常
Nice work, Doctor.\nAll systems go.
哇哈哈!
Boo-ya!
看我的飞行服
My flight suit.
哦也! 再来一次 万能的我...
Oh, yeah! Once again, the mighty...
到手了!
I've got it!
月亮是我的了!
I've got the moon!
天鹅湖公演
还来得及!
I can make it!
- 等等!
- Kevin!\n- Wait a minute!\n- Kevin!
加油 加油啊!
Come on, come on!
他还没来
He's still not here.
他来干什么? 是他不要我们了
Why would he come?\nHe gave us up.
可我们拉钩钩了!
But he pinkie promised!
宝贝们 丫头们 该上场了!
Girls, girls, places!
老师 现在不行! 我们还在等人
No, we can't start yet!\nWe're still expecting someone.
能再等一小会吗?
Can we just wait a few more minutes?
好吧 就一小会哦
All right.\nBut just a few more minutes.
他不会来了 姐妹们
He's not coming, guys.
Gru! Gru 听得到吗?
Gru! Gru, can you hear me?
快 我们必须尽快告诉他 必须快!
Quick, we have to warn him, and fast!
好的 好的 那是图书馆
Okay, okay. There's the library.
那是第三大道 舞蹈室在...
That's Third Street.\nThe dance studio...
那里! 就在那儿! 到了到了!
There! There! There it is!
抱歉 老兄 表演已经结束了
Sorry, buddy. Show's over.
结束了?
Over?
Margo Edith和Agnes的爸爸
想要孩子交出月亮!
Vector 开门!
Vector, open up!
先把月亮交出来 我们再谈
First give me the moon.\nThen we'll talk.
- Gru先生!\n- 闭嘴 小家伙
- Mr. Gru!\n- Zip it, Happy Meal.
把孩子还给我
Now, the girls.
不过 我还想和她们多呆一会
Actually, I think I'll hold on to them\na little while longer.
不要!
No!
哦也! 急死你丫的!
Oh, yeah! Unpredictable!
听好了 你这个疯子
Listen close, you little punk.
等我进去之后 你就只有跪地求饶的份儿了!
When I get in there,\nyou are in for a world of pain!
哎哟 我好怕哦!
I'm really scared!
他不会放过你的
He is gonna kick your butt.
热追踪导弹
神马? 竟敢揍我的鲨鱼!
What? He punched my shark!
逃生舱
他在那儿!
There he is!
Gru 坚持住
Hang on, Gru.
不要!
Oh, no!
孩子们在Vector手里 追!
Vector has the girls. Go!
飞船怎么了? 又变大了!
What happened to the ship?\nIt's big again!
- 等会儿复原的月亮才叫大!\n- 你说什么?
- Not as big as the moon\nis going to be! - What?
物体质量越大\n缩小射线的效用消失得就越快!
The larger the mass of an object,\nthe quicker the effects\nof the shrink ray wear off!
我把它命名为Nefario定律 (博士的姓)
I call it the Nefario Principle.
其实是刚想出来的
I just came up with it now,\nactually.
坏了!
Oh, no!
我最邪恶
看见了吗?
Did you see that?
- Vector! 快过来!
- Vector!\n- Vector! Help!\n- Vector!
- 回头!\n- 嘿!
- Over here!\n- Hey!
小丫头片子吵什么吵?
What are you girls\ndoing back there?
快看月亮!
The moon!
小心!
Watch out!
快 再近一点
Get as close in as you can.
非常好
You got it.
- Gru先生 我们在这儿!\n- Gru先生!
- Mr. Gru, up here!\n- Mr. Gru!
好的 孩子们! 孩子们!
Okay, girls! Girls!
- 准备好跳下来\n- 跳?
- You're going to have to jump.\n- Jump?
你疯了吗?
Are you insane?
别担心 我会接住你们的
Don't worry, I will catch you.
可你把我们送回孤儿院了!
You gave us back!
我知道 我知道 但我特别后悔
I know, I know. And it is\nthe worst mistake I ever made.
但你们现在必须跳
But you have to jump now.
没事的
It'll be okay.
好了 姑娘们
Okay, girls.
跳吧!
Jump now!
Margo 我会接着你的
Margo, I will catch you.
再也不扔下你了
And I will never let you go again.
- 别急嘛!\n- 不要!
- Not so fast!\n- No!
放开我!
Let me go!
Margo!
我来了 Margo 坚持住!
I'm coming, Margo.\nHang on!
没事了
I got you.
不要!
No!
他奶奶的
Oh, poop.
晚上好 好消息
This time, good triumphs,
月亮已经回归了
and the moon has been returned\nto its rightful place in the sky.
但是 案情依旧不明朗 疑团重重
But once again, law enforcement\nis baffled, leaving everyone to wonder,
到底谁是拯救月球的英雄?
who is this mysterious hero?
接下来他会做什么呢?
And what will he do next?
好了 小家伙们 该睡觉了
Okay, girls. Time for bed.
- 不要! 讲个故事嘛\n- 3只不想睡觉的小猫!
- Come on! We want a story.\n- Three sleepy kittens!
这个不行! 抱歉 那本书不小心被撕坏了
Oh, no! Sorry. That book was\naccidentally destroyed maliciously.
今天我们换本新书
Tonight we are going to read\na new book.
名字叫做
This one is called
大大独角兽 作者是谁呢?
One Big Unicorn by...\nWho wrote this?
是我! 我写的 瞧 也是木偶书!
Me! I wrote it.\nLook, it's a puppet book!
好了 看这个
Here, watch this.
这个是角!
That's the horn!
这本书一定超级好玩儿!
This is gonna be the best book ever!
小孩别学拍马屁 不过你说的确实没错
Not to pat myself on the back,\nbut, yes, it probably will be.
开始了
Here we go.
"大大独角兽 强壮又自由"
"One big unicorn, strong and free
"他觉得自己是世上最幸福的家伙"
thought he was happy as he could be.
"直到有天他遇到3只小猫"
Then three little kittens came around
"从此他的生活天翻地覆"
and turned his whole life\nupside down."
嘿 那个像我!
Hey, that one looks like me!
开什么玩笑? 这些是小猫咪!
No, what are you talking about?\nThese are kittens!
如有雷同 纯属巧合
Any relation to persons living or dead\nis completely coincidental.
"她们时而让他捧腹"
"They made him laugh.
"时而又哭笑不得"
They made him cry.
"那句再见 他真不该说"
He never should have said goodbye.
"现在他知道 他和那3只小猫"
And now he knows he could never part
"永远都分不开"
from those three little kittens
"她们改变了他的生活"
that changed his heart.
"完了"
The end."
好了 该睡觉了
Okay, all right. Good night.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
不是吧 不要!
No, no!
好吧
All right.
不是刚亲过你吗?
Didn't I get you already?
她们超棒吧!
They're very good!
我为你自豪 儿子
I'm so proud of you, Son.
不愧是个合格奶爸!
You've turned out to be\na great parent!
果然是遗传我
Just like me.
不过也许更优秀
Maybe even better.
不 我就算了 你们玩吧
No, I'm fine. Go ahead.
不了 不要!
No, no, no!
嘿 Carl! 过来
Hey, Carl! Hey.
不对 不对 不对
No, no, no.
我来 我来 我来
Me, me, me.
John?
不不 是我 我来
No, no. Me, me, me.
哦 不是吧
Oh, poop.
不是吧!
Oh, no!
犯规! 住手!
Stop! Stop!
你好呀 我是Gru
Hello, I am Gru.
回去工作了 回去工作了 回...
Back to work, back to work!\nBack to...